RUSSELL MORBEY

Software Engineer

Email: russellmorbey@hotmail.co.uk

Link: https://www.linkedin.com/in/russell-morbey-706063246/

ABOUT ME

I'm a personable, creative and detail focused Software Engineer. As well as in general an all-round supporter of people. Before taking the leap into software development I worked at various Special Educational Needs Schools across London over an 8 year period and before that, had intensive training for 4 years at East 15 Acting school. While working in schools I got my first glimpse into the world of coding and software development. I would assist the students in an hour of code a week. We built a Lego robot and were able to control its movements using simple lines of code. Combining my interests of building things and the possibility of tech led me to start my journey with Makers. What excites me most about tech is the seemingly unlimited potential to develop software that will have a positive impact on its users and the people around them. Software that can support people from all walks of life, especially for those who are overlooked.

PROJECTS

Project Name	Description	Technologies
<u>Palendar</u>	A web app from scratch. Finding a day to socialise with your friends, made easier.	MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, HTML5, CSS3, Jest, Cypress, React testing Library. Agile Methodologies
<u>Bettah</u>	A clone of Facebook	JavaScript, Node.js, Express, Handlebars, HTML5, CSS3, Jest, MongoDB, Cypress. Agile Methodologies
<u>MakersBnB</u>	A clone of AirBnB	Ruby, Rspec, Sinatra, Capybara, CSS3, HTML5, PostgreSQL. Agile Methodologies

EDUCATION

Software Engineer	BA Acting and Contemporary Theatre 1st Class
Makers Academy - 16 week Intensive Bootcamp	East 15 Acting School
04/2022 - 07/2022	2009 – 2013

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineering Intern

Goodlord

10/2022 - 01/2023

- Built automation scrapers in python to automate filling in council forms for changes of occupancy. Used
 my fresh understanding of python and selenium to support the other interns when they came across
 blockers.
- Added new React component functions to the tenancy journey to support flow throughout the platform, while adding accessibility and value to the customers. Helped to support the other interns with React questions and blockers while working on their tickets.
- Using Microsoft Azure Form recognizer with machine learning to teach a model to identify fields on a bank statement to pass and collect the information through a C# parser.

SEN Class Room Teaching Assistant

Samuel Rhodes School

02/2020 - 12/2021

- Being neurodiverse myself and displaying my own personal strengths and weaknesses. Using my skills
 of empathy I showed them that no matter their diagnosis, everyone has a personal basket of skills that
 are just as valid and valued as others. Empowering them to achieve their goals.
- Using my years of experience and leadership skills I often trained and mentored new TA's and provided feedback to higher management.
- While leading communication and self-independence lessons I identified the lack of accessible resources, so using my initiative skills I built and delivered tailor made resources from scratch.

- Using my skills of adaptability I worked in a range of different schools and environments that would often change from day to day. From mainstream to SEN Pupil Referral Units. Adapting to new environments quickly and injecting my skills into the team, to support the needs of the students.
- Using my combined skills of personal resilience and emotional compassion I was able to proactively
 defuse high pressure physical situations between multiple students which would have ended up putting
 the students safety in danger. Often culminating in having to reassure and console a student who
 attacked me in the process.
- Using my skills of quick learning and intuition management progressed me to working with some of the most challenging 1:1's in the schools. Where I'd work with several 1:1's over a day as I provided a calm and supportive environment as I successfully met their additional needs.